RG 074:027, Charles William Manwaring Genealogical Papers
Connecticut State Library
Charles William Manwaring genealogical papers
1861-1929
bulk 1891-1905
Connecticut State Library
Manwaring, Charles William, 1829-1905
3 cubic feet
Includes thirty four notebooks of genealogical notes, including one the Bull family; preliminary papers for a digest of probate records; Windsor, CT vital statistics; newspaper clippings; correspondence; a personal ledger; photographs; and some genealogical notes collected by Mary E. Manwaring.
RG074_027
1929-001
Biographical Note
Charles William Manwaring was born in Waterford, New London County, Conn., May 9, 1829. A builder and contractor, Mr. Manwaring became interested in genealogical research in later life. At the age of 70, he decided to develop a concise and durable form for the original probate record books of Connecticut, then located at the State Capitol and the Hall of Records in Hartford. Excessive use and time had reduced their accessibility. For the rest of his life, Mr. Manwaring labored under great physical disability as he battled cancer and still succeeded in producing three volumes for "A Digest of the Early Connecticut Probate Records, 1635-1750." He died on August 20, 1905, the day after completing the third volume.
Scope and Content
Includes thirty four notebooks of genealogical notes, including one the Bull family; preliminary papers for a digest of probate records; Windsor, CT vital statistics; newspaper clippings; correspondence; a personal ledger; photographs; and some genealogical notes collected by Mary E. Manwaring.
Arrangement
Arranged by document types.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Persons:
Manwaring, Charles William, 1829-1905; Manwaring, Mary
Family Names:
Bull family
Places:
Connecticut -- Genealogy; Windsor (Conn.) -- Vital statistics
Document Types:
Correspondence; News clippings; Photographs; Research notes
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
Given to the State Library by Miss Mary Manwaring in 1929.
Container List
- Series 1. Genealogical notes, 1897-1902
  - Memorandum notebooks, 1897-1902; 34 items + loose papers (Box 1)
    One notebook covers the Bull family.
  - Preliminary papers for the digest, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Windsor vital statistics, 1 envelope (Box Item 7)
    Includes notebook 14a.
- Series 2. Correspondence, 1861-1905; bulk 1891-1905
  - Abbott - Avery, 1898-1904 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bacon - Bateman, 1861 - 1901 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bates - Benedict, 1899-1903 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Benton - Binell, 1898-1904 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bishee - Bryant, 1897-1904, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bull - Butler, 1901-1904, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cady - Collins, 1898-1904 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cook - Cunningham, 1898-1904 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Daly - Downes, 1894-1902 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Eastland - Ensey, 1898-1904 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Farwell - Ford, 1898-1904 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gardner - Gunthrie, 1899-1904 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hamilton - Hawley, 1899-1904, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Hibbard - Howe, 1893-1903 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hoyt - Hyde, 1897-1904 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Jackson - Jones, 1897-1904 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Keep - Knapp, 1891-1902 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Langdon - Longsdorf, 1897-1904, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lord - Lyon, 1898-1903 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Manwaring - McCartney, 1893-1904, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - McDowell - Moulton, 1897-1903, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Olmsted - Park, 1898-1904 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Parkhurst, 1895-1901, undated (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Peck - Perkins, 1899-1905, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Perry - Proudfit, 1898-1904 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ransom - Robertson, 1897-1904 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Robinson - Roe, 1897-1904 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Rogers - Savage, 1901-1902 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Scott - Sheldon, 1896-1902, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Shephard, 1898-1903 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Shurtleff - Slone, 1899-1905 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Smith, Alex - Smith, Charles, 1899-1901, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Eliza Stewart, 1902-1903 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - Smith, John Cotton - Smith, Mary L., 1898-1904 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Snow - Swain, 1899-1905 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Taft - Vibbert, 1897-1903 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Wakeman - Wells, Mary, 1897-1902 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Wells, N.A. - Wyman, 1897-1903 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Series 3. Newspaper clippings, 1894-1901
  - Turn of the century newspapers (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - New London, 250 years old, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Old prison house, old bridge, Newgate Prison, other old buildings (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Obituaries (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Genealogical articles (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Trinity Church Chronicle, 1895-1898 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets, 1898-1903, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1899-1901 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
- Series 4. Personal ledger, 1868-1871
  - Ledger (Box Item 8)
- Series 5. Photographs, 1888-1914, undated
  - Elisha and Clarissa Perkins, undated; 2 daguerreotypes (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Elisha and Clarissa Perkins are the grandparents of Charles W. Manwaring.
  - Emily Perkins, undated; tintype (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Emily Perkins was the wife of William Hurlbut Manwaring.
  - Miscellaneous photographs and postcards, 1888-1914, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Series 7. Mary E. Manwaring genealogical notes, 1887-1929, undated
  - Champlin-Hazard family, 1904-1928, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Manwaring family, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Perkins-Starr-Seabury-Shipman families, 1887-1925, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Phillips family, 1913-1925, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Williams family, 1896-1916, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Avery family; Denison family; Perry family; Pray-Ayer family; Robertson family, 1916-1929, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Rhode Island news clippings; Foreward to In Old Narragansett; postcards, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - News clippings, 1904-1925, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)